<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home | WatchNationPro.com </title>
    <description>Love watches? Look for the perfect watch guide, tips and reviews to save money, make life easier, work smarter and earn more money and respect following the latest trends in watch industry.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 11:23:49 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 11:23:49 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Smartwatch for Elderly People</title>
        <description>&lt;!-- TOC depthFrom:1 depthTo:6 withLinks:1 updateOnSave:1 orderedList:0 --&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#smartwatches-for-elderly&quot;&gt;Smartwatches for Elderly&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#apple-watch-6&quot;&gt;Apple Watch 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#samsung-galaxy-watch-3&quot;&gt;Samsung Galaxy Watch 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fitbit-versa-3&quot;&gt;Fitbit Versa 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#lively-call&quot;&gt;Lively Call&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#freedom-guardian&quot;&gt;Freedom Guardian&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- /TOC --&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;smartwatches-for-elderly&quot;&gt;Smartwatches for Elderly&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elderly people at our home require extra care.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a breezy evening, and sam was sitting in the veranda thinking about his old aged mom, Celina. She was turning ill and her eye sights were blurred because of diabetic and other health conditions. She could not see properly and fell down yesterday while walking in the garden. It took fifteen minutes for their family members to realize that Celina had fallen down. She was taken to the hospital to find out her health conditions. Doctor measured Celina’s heartbeat, diabeties level, body temperature and said that all were normal. Sam was relieved there after. Now, sam is watching his mom sipping her coffee, while his mobile received a call from his office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam thinks about the quarrels with his mom Celina on how she used to shout at him when he assigned a person to accompany and monitor her. Celina thinks that it is intruding her independence. She hated travelling to the hospital often and did not like the lengthy procedure to undergo various medical tests. Sam had to wait at the hospital and get the test reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have our Sam’s and Celina’s at our home who suffer and fear the consequence of bad health for elderly people at our home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine the cost incurred for the hospital visits and all the medical the medical tests and reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All these problem can be solved through one solution. Yes!! It is possible!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the use of smartwatch designed for elderly people. Smartwatches will help, giving you the ability to monitor movement, heart rate, contact emergency services, and notify your nearest and dearest automatically if someone falls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the marketplace is flooded with choices, so how do you opt for the best one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Go through this list of best smartwatches for elderly to find your next smartwatch or one a friend or family member will love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These devices aren’t just fun accessories but actual life-saving technology beneficial for elderly folks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;apple-watch-6&quot;&gt;Apple Watch 6&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/apple-watch-6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Smartwatch-for-elderly&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think  about smartwatch, and there’s a good chance the Apple Watch springs to mind.  It is a favorite choice for the tech-savvy and Apple lovers alike, and it is much more than just a flashy gadget.   The Apple Watch Series 6 includes an assortment of features ideal for elderly people trying to maintain independence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Pros&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Cons&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Top-notch Heart rate monitoring with built-in Echocardiogram&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Good emergency notifications capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Finds if user falls on the ground&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Costly when compared to other brands&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Less compatible with non-apple devices&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with other top of line smartwatches, Apple Watch has GPS capabilities, the ability to make and receive calls in addition to texts, and check social media. Apple Watch includes some fairly substantial emergency notification attributes, too.  It can inform emergency responders if it finds a sudden fall of the person wearing it or perhaps an abnormal heart rate.  These features have proven to be more reliable and have saved a lot of lives over recent years. Apple6 smartwatch may be the top of the lineup, but that also means it includes is quite costly.  The battery life is something that also leaves us to be desired, and it does not always work well with non-Apple tablets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/buy-now.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy-now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;samsung-galaxy-watch-3&quot;&gt;Samsung Galaxy Watch 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/samsung-galaxy-watch-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;samsung-galaxy-watch-3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Samsung’s smartwatch also includes excellent health and security features, such as fall detection, the same as the Apple Watch. It can monitor stress levels and heart rate, also, and inform you once you want to unwind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;table table-bordered&quot;&gt;
    &lt;thead&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Pros&lt;/th&gt;
            &lt;th&gt;Cons&lt;/th&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
    &lt;tbody&gt;
        &lt;tr&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Larger display&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Works well with android devices&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Voice to text facility&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
            &lt;td&gt;
            &lt;ul&gt;
            &lt;li&gt;Less compatible with non-apple devices&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
            &lt;/td&gt;
        &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comparison to Apple Watch, it has got a considerably bigger display, which means larger text if your eyes are not so sharp .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is water-resistant, also, and contains voice to text capacities which may make texting a great deal simpler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This view is excellent for Android users, since the operating system will function better compared to pairing up an iPhone using a non-Apple Watch. If your loved one isn’t necessarily tech-savvy, read on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/buy-now.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy-now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fitbit-versa-3&quot;&gt;Fitbit Versa 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/fitbit.png&quot; alt=&quot;fitbit&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of easy, Fitbit has been viewed among the very awkward alternatives in regards to smartwatches.Fcitbit is just one of those big titles in fitness-focused watches.   It’s an always-ON screen so there’s no need to type in your password each time that you need to utilize it. Additionally, it’s its very own internal GPS tracker that means that you can wear it outside on a walk and leave your telephone in your home. Though the simplistic layout may be helpful for most, the Versa 3 will lack a few of the characteristics which make smartwatches perfect for seniors.  There are not any sudden fall notifications as well as the automated contact characteristics which make Apple Watch or Samsung Galaxy Watch useful are severely lacking.In case you’ve got an iPhone, bear in mind Fitbit does not play flawlessly with Apple products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/buy-now.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy-now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lively-call&quot;&gt;Lively Call&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrary to the Apple Watch or Samsung Galaxy Watch, the Lively includes its 24/7 emergency support you may use for assistance at any moment. If a drop or whenever you press the watch’s emergency button, then Lively will try to contact you. It is going to notify a close relative or caretaker then should you require assistance. Among the serious drawbacks is its mobile compatibility. This can cause a problem for those using older devices that can not run the most recent operating system. The Lively Wearable two is a device created only for seniors. It’s a huge screen for simple reading and an additional loudspeaker for simple listening. It is still slick and fashionable, which means you won’t seem strange from other sporting similar devices. Among the other big advantages of this unit is its unbelievable battery life, with around 4 weeks of constant wearing. You won’t need to remember to charge it nightly or even take it off. Additionally, it is water-resistant; therefore, it can remain on your wrist in the tub or shower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/buy-now.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy-now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;freedom-guardian&quot;&gt;Freedom Guardian&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The working of Freedom Guardian Watch is very similar to the Lively.   One of the most significant plus points is its two-way communicating attribute.  Freedom Guardian works similarly to a walkie-talkie, and you’re able to connect 24/7 to emergency services or receive non-emergency assistance. The easy-to-use screen is another plus.   Plus, it has all of the features you wish to stay safe, including sudden fall notifications, GPS monitoring, and medication reminders. It’s essential to be aware that the Freedom watch is only compatible with AT&amp;amp;T support, which means if you have any other cellular supplier, you will have to receive another plan.
Additionally, it lacks several advanced features like heart rate monitoring and stress level testing.  Nonetheless, it’s cheap, and the monthly cost comes in at $20.We all need to maintain our independence as we got old, and technology is making it easier and easier to do so.  These watches are just the start of the technology you can put into your loved one’s homes to assist them to have happy and comfortable golden decades.   Harness or click here to get more technology that may help seniors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;//assets/images/buy-now.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;buy-now&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <!---
        <link>http://localhost:4000//smartwatch-for-elderly/</link>-->
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//smartwatch-for-elderly/</guid>
        
        
        <category>Smartwatch</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
